Aiman Rizwan

Address: 1 Boughlone Way Bellingham Portlaoise, R32 CD5Y
Phone No: (+353) 830813921 | Visa: Stamp 1G
Email: aimanrizwan101@gmail.com | Linkedin

PROFILE

Graduate Software Engineering with a strong STEM foundation, proficient in software development, systems integration, and technology architecture. Engaged in staying at the forefront of technological advancements and deploying expertise to solve complicated issues and accomplish business achievement.

EDUCATION

University of Limerick

Limerick, Ireland

Master of Science in Software Engineering (Data Analytics)

Sept 2021 - Aug 2022

Cumulative GPA: 3.23 /4.00

Government College Women's University

Sialkot, Pakistan

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

Sept 2016 - Jul 2020

Cumulative GPA: 3.41 /4.00

SKILLS & CERTIFICATIONS

• Languages & Frameworks:

Front End: JavaScript, HTML, CSS

• Back End: Spring MVC

• Database: SQL

• Testing Tools: Jmeter

- Integrated Development Environment (IDE): Visual Studio, Eclipse, IntelliJ IDEA
- Software & tools: Java, Linux, Kubernetes, Python, GitHub, JIRA, Jupyter, Bitbucket, Postman, Jenkins, Soap UI, Microsoft Visio, Lucid chart, Adobe Illustrator.

SQL Essential Training (Completed: May 2023) — LinkedIn Learning

• Explored the fundamentals of SQL, including the basic structure of databases and mastering the most important SQL query syntax.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Openet, Amdocs

Dublin, Ireland

Graduate Software Developer

Oct 2022 - Apr 2023

- Deep understanding of DevOps operations, including addressing significant code bugs and leading continuous improvement initiatives that resulted in a 20% boost in total system reliability.
- Exhibited troubleshooting abilities while dealing with complex tasks, resulting in an unforeseen 30% decrease in system downtime and an immediate 25% improvement in response time.
- Collaborated with an international team, analyzed software issues, and integrated new technologies and platforms, achieving a thirty percent rise in software functionality and a 20% increase in team productivity.
- Optimal Jira ticket management, prioritized tasks, and accelerated resolution of issues. Reduced resolution time by 20%, boosting team efficiency.

McDonald's/Burger King

Limerick, Ireland

Crew Member

Nov 2021 - Jun 2022

• Customer satisfaction improved by 20% as a result of multitasking in a fast-paced atmosphere, responding to inquiries, and guaranteeing on-time delivery.

University of Limerick

Student Ambassador (Volunteer)

Limerick, Ireland Sept 2021 - Jan 2022

• Delivered thorough assistance and strategically offered ten programs, resulting in an enhanced reputation for the university and an upsurge of 20% in feedback from students.

Government Third Level Institution

Data Entry Associate (Intern)

Sialkot, Pakistan Jun 2019 - Nov 2019

- Achieved flawless organization of data and keep track of uploading data into the customer relationship management (CRM) system, sustained 100% accuracy.
- Developed Excel sheets and Word documents and facilitated data input, storage, manipulation, and interpretation, achieving a 95% client satisfaction rating based on positive feedback and low complaint instances.

PROJECTS

University of Limerick

Thesis, Analysis on Rowing Data Using Python and ML Techniques

- Built a data analysis and machine learning project for a rowing data-set using Python libraries such as NumPy, Pandas, and Seaborn, resulting in a 15% boost in data processing performance.
- Implemented robust data preparation procedures and used unsupervised learning algorithms to reduce the processing time by 25% and find significant patterns.
- Concluded the analysis by demonstrating that the application of dimension reduction techniques, specifically principal component analysis, reduced the AUC score by 10% without compromising accuracy.

University of Limerick

Cloud Kitchen Project

- Developed a web-based food delivery service using Java programming language.
- Engineered RESTful APIs with the Spring framework to enable communication between microservices, resulting in a 30% improvement in data exchange efficiency.
- Designed and implemented microservices architecture, leading to a 40% increase in system functionality.
- Followed Agile methodologies, including Scrum, for iterative and incremental development, yielding a 20% reduction in project delivery time and increased customer satisfaction, and enabling quick adaptation to changes in customer requirements.
- Employed Azure DevOps for Continuous Development and Integration (CI/CD), enabling efficient code tracking with a 20% reduction in bug identification time, automated builds, and deployments.
- Constructed detailed project documentation to offer a comprehensive overview of the system architecture.

INTERESTS

• Graphic Designing, Hiking, Archery, Swimming, Traveling